Preliminary Inventory of the Lee V. Harris Papers, 1944-1955
Hoover Institution Archives
Lee V. Harris Papers,
1944-1955
69074
Harris, Lee V., 1897-1969
2 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize folder (1.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Writings, correspondence, photographs, maps, and memorabilia, relating to U.S. military operations in China during World War II, the Chinese Civil War, and the Indochinese War.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
United States. Army--Officers.; Indochinese War, 1946-1954.; World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--China.; China.; China--History--Civil War, 1945-1949.; Indochina.; United States--Armed Forces.; Military attachés.
Container List
- Correspondence with Brigadier General Millard C. Young, United States Air Force, Chief, Joint Subsidiary Plans Division, and others. 1955 January (Box 1)
- Correspondence with Colonel Harris in Saigon, Vietnam, 1950 August-1952 September (mostly in French or Vietnamese)
- Typescript manuscript, "Southeast Asia," an analysis of Russo-Chicom, combined strategy and plans. For use in his son-in-law's Naval War College thesis on the subject 'The Need for an Expanded Southeast Asia Treaty Organization'
- Personal experience monograph, Field Team no. 5, Executive Headquarters, prepared by Colonel Lee V. Harris, 1946
- Personal experience monograph, Field Team no 34, Executive Headquarters, prepared by Colonel Lee V. Harris, 1946
- Scrapbook
- 8 pictures (Burma-Road)
- Scrapbook and 20 photographs on the Marshall Mission
- 70 photographs (Indo-China, etc.)
- 3 flags and 1 pennant (Box 2)
- 8 large maps (Map-case Map case)
  - Stanford's general map of the world, 1964
  - 2 maps of China
  - The Far East, 1952
  - 3 maps of the Ledo-Burma Road (First Provisional Tank Group, Chinese-American)
  - Profile map "The Ledo-Burma Road"